Guide to the Frederick W. Hilles Manuscript Collection and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Frederick W. Hilles Manuscript Collection and Papers
1645-1979
GEN MSS 1429
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
70.47
(147 boxes) + 2 broadsides, 1 roll.
Manuscript collection and papers of Frederick W. Hilles. The manuscript collection includes correspondence and writings by James Boswell, Thomas and Jane Carlyle, Samuel Johnson, Joshua Reynolds, and members of their families. The papers include personal and professional correspondence; research files and writings; personal and family papers, including material related to Susan Morse Hilles and Charles Dewey Hilles; teaching materials from Hilles' tenure at Yale University and Temple University; and material documenting Hilles' service on the boards of the Yale Library Associates and the Yale University Press.
Hilles, Frederick W. (Frederick Whiley), 1900-1975
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Frederick W. Hilles (Yale 1922).
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection of correspondence and other manuscript writings by James Boswell, Thomas Carlyle, Samuel Johnson, Joshua Reynolds, and members of their families, collected by Frederick W. Hilles. Also includes manuscripts, correspondence, personal papers and classroom materials from Frederick W. Hilles.
Manuscript collection and papers of Frederick W. Hilles. The manuscript collection includes correspondence and writings by James Boswell, Thomas and Jane Carlyle, Samuel Johnson, Joshua Reynolds, and members of their families. The papers include personal and professional correspondence; research files and writings; personal and family papers, including material related to Susan Morse Hilles and Charles Dewey Hilles; teaching materials from Hilles' tenure at Yale University and Temple University; and material documenting Hilles' service on the boards of the Yale Library Associates and the Yale University Press.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Frederick W. Hilles Manuscript Collection, 1645-1969. II. Frederick W. Hilles Papers, 1775-1979.
Appendix: List of Materials transferred to the Boswell Papers
The Pottle catalog numbers have been included.
Boswell, James
ALS to [John] Boswell (L 161)
[early 1768?] Tuesday
1 p., with address
ALS to Charles Burney, Jr (L 337)
[n.d., no place]
1 p., with address
ALS to Bruce Campbell (L 351)
1782 May 1, Edinburgh
2 p., with address
ALS and AL (in the 3rd person) to Sir John Hussey
Delaval, Baron Seaton Delaval
1795 Feb 27, London. 1 p., with address (L 409, L 410)
[1795] Apr 9, London. 1 p., with address
AL (in the 3rd person) to Ozias Humphry (L 645)
[1791 Jan 3]
1 p., with address
ALS to Thomas Percy (L 1065)
1784 Jul 8, Carlisle
1 p., with address
Accompanied by: Engraving of Boswell
ALS to Isaac Reed (L 1094)
[1790] Apr 21
1 p., with address
ALS (in French) to Jean Jacques Rousseau (L 1119.1)
1766 Jan 4, Lyon
4 p., including address
ALS to Tobias Smollett (L 1162)
1768 Mar 14, Edinburgh
3 p., with address
ALS to John Spottiswoode (L 1183)
1786 Mar 25, York
2 p., with address
ALS to [John] Wauchope (L 1274)
[1781 Feb 22]
3 p., with address
[Hector, Edmund]
AL (draft; incomplete) to [James Boswell] (C 1522)
[1785 Feb 1]
1 p.
Parr, Samuel
ALS to James Boswell (C 2184)
1791 Dec 11, Halton
3 p., with address
Reynolds, Sir Joshua
AL (photocopy) to James Boswell
[ca. 1775 April ?] Monday
1 p., with address
5 ALS (photostats) to Edmund Burke:
[1768 between Sep 14 & Oct 18, Paris]
1784 Aug 24, London
[1784 Dec 18, London]
1789 Jul 25, London
1791 Jan 25, London
Related Materials
In addition to the materials described in this finding aid, a number of pieces were transferred to the Boswell Papers. These are listed in an appendix.
Authors, English -- 18th century; Authors, English -- 19th century; College teachers -- United States; English literature -- 18th century; English literature -- 19th century; Manuscripts -- Collectors and collecting -- United States; College teachers -- United States -- 20th Century; Boswell, James, 1740-1795; Carlyle, Jane Welsh, 1801-1866; Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881; Hilles, Charles Dewey, 1867-1949; Hilles, Frederick W. (Frederick Whiley), 1900-1975; Hilles, Susan Morse, 1905-2002; Johnson, Samuel, 1649-1703; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; Temple University. Department of English; Yale Library Associates; Yale University. Department of English; Yale University Press
- Frederick W. Hilles Manuscript Collection, 1645–1969; Series I; 17.94; 41 boxes + 1 broadside.
  Scope and Contents
  Manuscript collection of Frederick W. Hilles, including correspondence and writings by James Boswell, Thomas and Jane Carlyle, Samuel Johnson, Joshua Reynolds, and members of their families.
  Arrangement
  Series I is organized into four subseries: Literary and Historical Manuscripts, Carlyle Manuscripts, Johnson Manuscripts, and Miscellaneous Prints and Art.
  - Literary and Historical Manuscripts, 1688–1951
    Arranged alphabetically by author.
    - Abington, Mrs., 1789 August 11; 1789 August 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Two autograph letters, written in the third person, to Mr. Humphrys.
    - Adam, James, 1789 June 17 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Autograph letter, signed to Mr. More, from London, 1 page.
    - Addison, Joseph, 1714 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Ambrose Philips, 1 page.
    - Aitken, Lucy, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Baillie, 1 page.
    - Alexander, C. F., undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Long, from Edinburgh, 3 pages.
    - Alford, Henry, 1864 June 22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Autograph letter, signed, to his cousin, from Canterbury, 2 pages.
    - Allen, J., 1778 January (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Burden, from Lisbon, 3 pages. On the verso of page 3, there is an autograph manuscript note, signed with initials, from Lady Frances Chambers regarding the death of Thomas Chambers.
    - Allen, Ralph, 1736 November 17 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Autograph letter, signed, to his sister, from Bath, 2 pages.
    - Allum, W., 1794 July 19 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Autograph letter, signed, to George Dyer, from New York, 3 pages.
    - Amelia, Princess, 1810 September 27 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Neale, 2 pages.
    - Arblay, Frances (Burney) d', 1776 October 17 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Fragment of an autograph manuscript describing the behavior of the King and Queen at a performance of All in Wrong and Cross Purposes, 1 page. A sketch in ink of the theatre titled "a very Pretty Little Bit of confusion" is present on the verso.
    - Arblay, Frances (Burney) d' (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Portions of autograph manuscript diary, 27 leaves, with wrapper.
    - Arblay, Frances (Burney) d', 1782 November 14 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Autograph letter, signed with initials, to Charles Burney, from Brightelmstone, 4 pages.
    - Arblay, Frances (Burney) d', ? March 22 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Autograph letter, signed with initials, to Rosette Burney, with address "Mrs. Meeke, Mrs. Phillips," 2 pages.
    - Arblay, Frances (Burney) d', ? March 22 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Autograph letter, signed with initials, to Rosette Burney, with address "Continual avocations, & total want of leisure," from London, 2 pages.
    - Arblay, Frances (Burney) d', 1800 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Autograph letter to Rosette Burney, from West Hamble, Dorking, 3 pages.
    - Arblay, Frances (Burney) d', 1785 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Autograph letter, signed with initials, to Mary (Hamilton) Dickenson, from Twickenham, 4 pages.
    - Arblay, Frances (Burney) d', 1785 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mary (Hamilton) Dickenson, 2 pages. With a note on page 3 from Dr. Burney, in the third person and in the hand of Fanny Burney, declining an invitation from Lady Herries and Miss Hamilton.
    - Arblay, Frances (Burney) d', 1787 December 6 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mary (Hamilton) Dickenson, from Windsor, 4 pages.
    - Arnold, Matthew, 1873 December (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "My dear Walter," from Cobham, 1 page.
    - Arnold, Thomas, 1840 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, possibly Henry Foss, from Rugby, with a printed form containing the terms of Rugby School.
    - Ash, John, 1787 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Autograph letter in the third person to Sir Joseph Banks, 1 page.
    - Astle, Thomas, 1763 January 5 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, from London, 1 page. Accompanied by a manuscript song of twelve stanzas titled "The Songe of his Honor's songe the Nighte before he died" sung by the Earl of Essex the night before he died, transcribed by Thomas Astle and signed by Astle and and A. Gifford, 3 pages.
    - Aubrey, John, 1688 or 1689?; 1688–1689 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Autograph letter, signed with initials, to Anthony à Wood, from London, 2 pages. Accompanied by a corrected typescript, possibly by Frederick W. Hilles, about the letter, 13 pages.
    - Bacon, John, 1894 July 25 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Charles Grant, 3 pages.
    - Banks, Sir Joseph, 1820 March 18 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Daniel Lysons, 1 page.
    - Barbauld, Anna Letitia, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Harriet Martineau, 1 page.
    - Barrington, Daines, 1770 May 5 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      Autograph letter, signed to Thomas Percy, 2 pages.
    - Beattie, James, 1786 May 3 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Cadell, from Aberdeen, 1 page. Accompanied by an engraving of James Hay Beattie by J. Heath.
    - Beattie, James, 1783 April 25 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Alexander Chalmers, from Gordon Castle, 3 pages.
    - Beaumont, Sir George Howland, 1794 January 7 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Autograph letter, written in the third person, to Mr. Leader, from Dunmow, 1 page.
    - Beaumont, Sir George Howland, circa 1795; 1790–1800 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mary Palmer O'Brien, 3 pages.
    - Bentley, Richard, 1721?; 1721 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      Autograph letter to Dr. Mead, 8 pages.
    - Benwell, William, 1787 June (Box 2, Folder 34)
      Autograph manuscript essay, signed, titled " In What Arts Have the Moderns Excelled the Ancients? ," Trinity College, 31 leaves.
    - Berkeley, Eliza, 1799 December 28 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from London, 4 pages.
    - Bernard, Sir Thomas (Box 2, Folder 36)
      Autograph manuscript note titled The Ladies Society about the Society, 2 pages. Includes an autograph note, signed with initials, by Lady Frances Chambers on page 2.
    - Bernard, Sir Thomas, 1818 June 3 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Frances (Wilton) Chambers, from London, 1 page.
    - Berry, Mary, Wednesday, January 29 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, 1 page.
    - Berwick, Edward, circa 1787; 1782–1792 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      Autograph manuscript, signed, titled " An Account of a Tour to the Giant's Causeway in the year 1787 ," describing a tour from September 11-17, 1787, 26 pages. A note on page 26 indicates that the manuscript was written as a letter: "Pardon Madam the tedious length of this letter..."
    - Bickersteth, Edward Henry, 1880 May 15 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Miss Martin, from London, 3 pages.
    - Bindley, James, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Percy, from London, 1 page.
    - Blair, Hugh, circa 1775; 1770–1780 (Box 35, Folder 918-919)
      A course of lectures on rhetoric and belles lettres, Edinburgh, circa 1775. Manuscript transcript in a contemporary hand of Blair's lectures, including portions omitted in the first published edition in 1783. 2 volumes bound in calf, gilt, with signature of R. W. Greatheed on inside front cover.
    - Blake, William, 1804 July 16 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      Autograph letter, signed, to William Hayley, from London, 3 pages.
    - Bourn, Abel, 1778 March 28 (Box 3, Folder 43)
      Autograph letter, signed, to his son, from Barnstable, 4 pages.
    - Bowles, William Lisle, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
      Autograph letter, signed, to J. G. Nicholls (i.e. John Gough Nichols), from Salisbury, 1 page.
    - Boxall, William, 1847 January 13 (Box 3, Folder 45)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir Charles Lock Eastlake, 4 pages.
    - Boxall, William, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Elizabeth Eastlake, from London, 4 pages.
    - Boydell, Mary, 1786 April 4 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      Autograph manuscript poem, signed with initials, beginning "If I'm as fair as Hebe…" with a note at the bottom of the page to John Ellis, from Cheapside, 1 leaf.
    - Britton, John (Box 33 (Oversize), Folder 903)
      A collection of autograph letters and manuscripts (in a volume labelled "Fine Arts of the English School, Letters & Mems") apparently compiled by John Britton for his autobiography; with prospectus advertising The Fine Arts of the English School, London, 1809 and Britton's five page index of the material. Material includes:
      1. Anderson, J. P., Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton, undated, Monday night, 2 pages.
      2. Davison, Alexander, Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton, 1807 February 20, London, 1 page.
      3. Flaxman, John, Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton, undated, 1 page, with address.
      4. Britton, John, "Gainsborough": autograph manuscript notes on four paintings by Gainsborough, undated, 1 page.
      5. Britton, John, Autograph letter, signed, (copy) to Earl Grey, June, 1 page.
      6. Hoare, Prince, Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton, October 1, London, 2 pages.
      7. Hoare, Prince, Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton, 1809 August 4, Beckenham, 4 pages, including address.
      8. Hope, Thomas, Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton, undated, 1 page.
      9. Hope, Thomas, Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton undated, 4 pages.
      10. Hope, Thomas, Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton undated, 3 pages.
      11. Hope, Thomas, Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton, 1810 June 10, Deepdene, 1 page.
      12. Hope, Thomas, Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton undated, 4 pages.
      13. Hunt, R., Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton, 1811 April 24, Stoke Newington, 1 page.
      14. Malone, Edmund, Autograph letter (in the 3rd person) to John Britton, undated, 1 page with address.
      15. Nollekens, Joseph, Autograph letter (in the 3rd person) to Mr. Bond, 1811 May 17, 1 page.
      16. Phillips, Thomas, Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton, undated, 2 pages.
      17. Phillips, Thomas, Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton, 1810 May 21. 1 page, with address.
      18. Porden, W, Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton, 1810 March 20, 2 pages.
      19. Britton, John, "Reynolds": first page of the introduction intended for A Biographical Memoir of Sir Joshua Reynolds Knight by Northcote, 1 page. On verso: Explanation of the order on the cover: designed by J. L. Bond, Architect...
      20. Hoare, Prince, "Garrick between Tragedy and Comedy": autograph manuscript notes for part of the Epilogue to the Brothers spoken by Mrs. Yales, undated, 1 page.
      21. Watts, W. H, Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton, 1810 July 8, 1 page, with address.
      22. " The European Magazine, and London Review, For June, 1790. An Account of Richard Wilson, Esq, Landscape Painter, F. R. A. " Supposedly written by Mr. Hodges.
      23. Britton, John, "Wilson" autograph manuscript notes, undated, 1 page.
      24. Britton, John "Wilson" autograph manuscript notes, undated, 1 page.
      25. Britton, John, "Wilson" autograph manuscript notes, undated, 1 page. On verso: portion of autograph letter, signed, from Sir Joyce to John Britton, 1811 December 20.
      26. Britton, John, "Wilson" autograph manuscript notes, undated, 2 pages.
      27. Britton, John, "Wilson" autograph manuscript notes, undated, 1 page.
      28. Britton, John, "Wilson" autograph manuscript notes, undated, 1 page.
      29. Beaumont, Sir George, Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton, 1811 December 6, Dunmore, 2 pages, with address.
      30. Farington, Joseph, Autograph letter, signed, to John Britton, 1811 December 3, 1 page, with address.
      31. Taylor, Autograph letter (in the 3rd person) to John Britton, 1812 January 27, 1 page, including address.
      32. Wilson, Benjamin, Autograph letter, signed, to Lord Townshend, 1751 May 9, 1 page, with address.
    - Britton, John, 1832 May 24 (Box 3, Folder 48)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Morrison, 4 pages. Formerly laid in volume labelled on spine "Fine Arts of the British School..." and not included on John Britton's list.
    - Browne, Isaac Hawkins, 1757 (Box 3, Folder 49)
      Manuscript titled "Epode écrite en 1757..." possibly written by Isaac Hawkins Browne, 7 pages.
    - Browning, Robert, 1879 June 6 (Box 3, Folder 50)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Black, from London, 2 pages.
    - Brydges, Sir Samuel Egerton, 1834 November 20 (Box 3, Folder 51)
      Autograph letter, signed Chandos of Sudeley, to Mr. Cochrane, from Geneva, 8 pages.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1786 August 16 (Box 3, Folder 52)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Stephen Thurston Adey, 1 page.
    - Burke, Edmund, circa 1766 May 13; 1766 May 13 (Box 3, Folder 53)
      Autograph letter to James Barry, 3 pages. An autograph note, signed with initials, from Christopher Nugent to Barry is present on page 4.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1767 February (Box 3, Folder 54)
      Autograph letter to James Barry, 7 pages.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1767 April 26 (Box 3, Folder 55)
      Autograph letter, signed, to James Barry, 3 pages.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1767 August 24 (Box 3, Folder 56)
      Autograph letter to James Barry, 4 pages.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1768 July 19 (Box 3, Folder 57)
      Autograph letter, signed, to James Barry, from Gregories, 4 pages.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1769 October 8 (Box 3, Folder 58)
      Autograph letter, signed, to James Barry, from Gregories, 2 pages.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1788 August 1 (Box 3, Folder 59)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Charles Burney, from London, 2 pages. With a note by Fanny Burney on page 1, and accompanied by an engraving of Burke by J. Brown from a painting by Reynolds.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1791 November 1 (Box 3, Folder 60)
      Copy of a letter from Burke in an unidentified hand to Catherine II, Empress of Russia, from Beaconsfield, 4 pages.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1795 January 16 (Box 3, Folder 61)
      Autograph letter, signed, to the Chairman of the Commission of Public Accounts, from Beaconsfield, 2 pages. Bound in straight grain tan morocco gilt and accompanied by three engraved portraits of Burke.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1772 October 27 (Box 3, Folder 62)
      Autograph letter, signed, to William Dowdeswell, from Beaconsfield, 7 pages.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1772 November 7 (Box 3, Folder 63)
      Autograph letter, signed, to William Dowdeswell, from Broad Sanctuary, 5 pages.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1787 June 1 (Box 3, Folder 64)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Henry Dundas, 3 pages.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1775 May 12 (Box 4, Folder 65)
      Autograph letter, signed, to William Eden, 1 page.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1791 November 2 (Box 4, Folder 66)
      Autograph letter, signed, to John King, from Beaconsfield, 2 pages.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1794–1795 (Box 4, Folder 67)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Walker King, 1795 June 30, from Beaconsfield, 2 pages. Also includes: an autograph letter, signed, from Walker King to an unidentified recipient, 1795 July 2, from London, 4 pages; a copy of a letter from Joshua Reynolds, possibly in the hand of Mary Hyde, to an unidentified recipient, possibly Walker King, 1794 September 5, from Weymouth, 1 page; and an engraving of Burke by W. Read from a painting by Reynolds.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1795 January 21 (Box 4, Folder 68)
      Autograph letter, signed, to French Laurence, from Beaconsfield, 3 pages.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1796 February 27?; 1796 February (Box 4, Folder 69)
      Autograph letter, signed, to French Laurence, 3 pages.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1784 March 27 (Box 4, Folder 70)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir William Lee, from London, 3 pages.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1784 May 6 (Box 4, Folder 71)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Sir William Lee, from Beaconsfield, 3 pages.
    - Burke, Edmund, ? February 10 (Box 4, Folder 72)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Elizabeth Montagu, from London, 1 page.
    - Burke, Edmund, 1764 December 31 (Box 4, Folder 73)
      Autograph letter, signed, to William Young, from London, 2 pages.
    - Burke, Jane, 1797 January 17 (Box 4, Folder 74)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Venables, from Beaconsfield, 2 pages.
    - Burke, Sir John Bernard, 1854 July 5 (Box 4, Folder 75)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Watts, from Dublin, 3 pages.
    - Burnett, James, Lord Monboddo, 1779?; 1779 (Box 4, Folder 76)
      Autograph letter written in the third person to Charles Burney, from London, 2 pages.
    - Burney, Charles (1726-1814), 1767 October 20 (Box 4, Folder 77)
      Autograph manuscript poem titled " Ode on a Lady's Birthday Oct. 20th 1767 ," 2 pages.
    - Burney, Charles (1726-1814), 1778 (Box 4, Folder 78)
      Manuscript poem, possibly in the hand of Charles Burney, titled " To Mrs. Thrale on receiving from her a Gold Pen ," 2 pages.
    - Burney, Charles (1726-1814), 1794 November 28 (Box 4, Folder 79)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Joseph Cooper Walker, from Chelsea College, 3 pages. Accompanied by a photostat copy of an essay in Burney's hand on Coreggio, possibly done for Reynolds' catalogue of Ralphs Exhibition, 1 page.
    - Burney, Charles (1726-1814), 1789 October 2 (Box 4, Folder 80)
      Autograph letter to Frances (Burney) d'Arblay, from Chelsea College, 4 pages.
    - Burney, Charles (1757-1817), 1817 February 19 (Box 4, Folder 81)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Frances (Burney) d'Arblay, from Deptford, 4 pages.
    - Burns, Robert, undated (Box 4, Folder 82)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Charles Hay, 1 page, with an autograph manuscript poem by Burns titled " On the death of the late Lord President ," 1 leaf, in a brown morocco case.
    - Bury, Lady Charlotte Susan Maria, undated (Box 4, Folder 83)
      Autograph letter, written in the third person, to Madame Dey, 2 pages.
    - Butler, Henry Montagu, 1897 April 5 (Box 4, Folder 84)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Archdeacon, from Lyndhurst, 4 pages.
    - Caillard, Bernard, 1779 June 15 (Box 4, Folder 85)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Copenhagen, 2 pages.
    - Carter, Elizabeth, 1789 (Box 4, Folder 86)
      Autograph manuscript prayer, 2 leaves.
    - Carter, Elizabeth, 1753 August 13 (Box 4, Folder 87)
      Autograph letter, signed F. E. Carlington, to Samuel Richardson, from Ramsgate, 3 pages.
    - Cassan, Matthew, 1801 August 6 (Box 5, Folder 88)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Stephen (Mears) Cassan, Balbriggen, 3 pages.
    - Cassan, Matthew, 1801 December 27; 1802 August 20 (Box 5, Folder 89)
      Two autograph letters, signed, to Lady Frances (Wilton) Chambers, with a note by Lady Chambers, signed with initials, on page 4 of the second letter.
    - Cassan, Stephen?, 1802 January 20 (Box 5, Folder 90)
      Autograph letter, written in the third person, to Lady Frances (Wilton) Chambers, 1 page.